Armin Rahmati

Software Engineer







Profile

Motivated backend developer with 2 years of experience in developing web applications and APIs. Diligent in solving complex problems, collaborating effectively within teams, and learning new technologies. Currently studying cyber security at Amirkabir University of Technology.

Experience

Tasu Ventures

Apr 2024- Jan 2024

- Integrated social media functionalities using the Facebook API, implemented web scraping, and applied design patterns.
- Managed asynchronous tasks using BullMQ, transactions, and promises. Participated in code reviews to maintain high code quality.
- implement unit/e2e tests and Prometheus log for all modules
- Role: backend developer

Technology Development Center of Noshirvani University

Jan 2023- Mar 2023

- Internship under the supervision of Dr. Mehdi Emadi
- Developed a buyer's request management system with geolocation to locate nearby car spare parts, and implemented a memory-efficient notification and message queuing system using a publish-
- subscribe model.
 Role: backend developer (node js).

Projects

Store Locator

- Developed a system for parts buyers to request parts from stores, receive inventory responses, track requests, view store locations on a map, and find the shortest route to the store. handle concurrent request operations without blocking the main execution thread.
- Node.is, Express, Docker, Geolocation API, Socket.io, PostgreSQL, Redis.

E-commerce

• Implemented features including multilingual support, order tracking, inventory management, role management, discounts, payment gateway, wishlist, shopping cart, and user/admin panel.

github

• Laravel, Tailwind, Livewire, MySQL.

Skills

 $typescript \mid Node.js \mid BullMQ \mid SQL \ (PostgreSQL, MySQL) \mid NoSQL \ (Redis) \mid Docker \mid Socket.io \mid Unit \ and \ Integration \ Testing \mid version \ control \mid CI/CD \ (GitHub \ Actions) \mid SOLID \mid Prior \ Stack: Laravel$

Familiar with

 $Linux (File System, Bash Script) \mid co\underline{mpiler \ design} \mid python(ML, \underline{Data} \ \underline{Visualization}, \underline{PyQt}) \mid \underline{Tail}\underline{w}ind \ \underline{CSS}$

Education

 amirkabir university of technology Masters degree Computer Cyber Security

September 2024

Babol Noshirvani University of Technology
 Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering, GPA:
 3/4

September 2020 - September 2024

Teaching Assistant - Babol Noshirvani

Dr. Hassan Nasiraee

Apr 2021- Jan 2021

Instructed students on fundamental networking concepts, protocols, and technologies, including TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, VLANs, and routing protocols Provided practical guidance on network simulation tools such as Cisco Packet Tracer and Wireshark